我收拾衣柜的时候
When I was going through my wardrobe
在地板上我发现了一个多余的发夹
I found an extra hairpin on the floor
那不算什么，我还在床上发现了她的头发
That's nothing, I found her hair in my bed.
我想，那只是另一出心力交瘁的悲剧，
Just another tragedy of a down-and-out, I guess
我所卖出的东西
For I'm selling the thing
代表了我的生命和我的幸福的一切...
That means every thing to my life...
有的女人，她们走到哪儿，欢乐就跟到哪儿；
Some women bring happines...
有些，则是及时行乐
wherever they go.Others, whenever they go.
我二者兼顾
I do both.
丈夫们乐意看到我来，
Husbands like tosee me come...
妻子们则喜欢送我走
wives prefer to seeme go.
她在那，那就是她
There she is.That's her.
她谁的丈夫没睡过啊?
Whose husband didn't she sleep with?
- 她现在跟谁在一起啊?- 谁知道
- Who's she with now?- Who knows.
- 她比我想的老- 看，看好
- She's older than I thought.- Look. Watch.
这会给她个教训
This will teach her.
对不起，Erlynne太太,但是那个账户已经
I'm sorry, Mrs Erlynne, but that account was closed.
被Fairchild太太停了
By Mrs Fairchild.
我希望你在我点Bordeaux酒之前告诉我就好了
I wish you'd told me before I ordered the Bordeaux.
什么Bordeaux酒, Erlynne太太?
What Bordeaux, Mrs Erlynne?
Joe, 你是我喜欢的那类男人
Joe, you're my kind of guy.
- 她在我后面吗?- 穿兰色衣服
- Is she behind me?- In the blue.
那就算在Kleghorn参议员的帐上吧
Charge it to Senator Kleghorn.
Fairchild太太边上坐的就是Kleghorn太太
That's Mrs Kleghorn sitting next to Mrs Fairchild.
- 世界可真小啊- 她左边的是Winters太太
- What a small world.- And Mrs Winters on her right.
哦，越来越小了
And getting smaller.
你要从后面走吗?
You wanna go outthe back?
不，如果你从后门走就再也别想从前面进来了，Joe
No, if you go out the back, you'll never come in the front, Joe.
淑女怎么来，便怎么走
A lady always leaves the way she came.
你看看她，我以为我丈夫更有品呢
I thought my husband had more taste.
听说你要走真难过，Erlynne太太
So sorry to hear you're leaving us, Mrs Erlynne.
我要退房？- 我给您备好账单
- I'm leaving you?- I'll prepare your bill.
我让你开个价，
I ask you to make me an offer
我不知道那会值多少
I don't know how much it will bring
虽然那并不算太多
It isn't a lot...
但那已经倾我所有
but it's all I've got
把老金戒也一起卖了？
Pooled by an old gold ring?
有时我一贫如洗，象个乞丐
It's known me as poor as a beggar
有时我挥金如土，象个国王
And it's known me as rich as a king
我既下过地狱，又上过天堂
And it's known me in hell And in heaven as well
把老金戒也一起卖了？
Pooled by an old gold ring?
我环境的突变...
My sudden changeing circumstance...
并不是我离开的唯一理由
was not the only reason for my departure.
夏季的意大利海滩吸引着富者和名人
The italian coast in summerattracts the rich and famous.
我没名气又穷
I'm infamous and poor.
挺接近的
Close enough.
一扇门关闭，另一扇开启了
One door closes,another opens.
有时那并不是你所期待的门
Sometimes that door isnot the one you expect.
我看到了我的机会并决定抓住
I saw my chance anddecided to take it.
Meg, 亲爱的，快过来
Meg, dear. Come along.Come along.
啊, Giuseppina
Ah, Giuseppina.
她是我的朋友，给她一个折扣
She's my friend.Give her a discount.
过来
Come here.
这是城里最好的手套店
It's the best glove shop in the city.
她会给你个好折扣
She'll give you a good discount.
你去吧，我会找到你丈夫的，别担心
You go along, I'll find yourhusband, don't worry.
这边请，女士
This way, madam.
这真漂亮
These are pretty.
- 你的手看上去差不多- 你说什么?
- Your hand looks about right.- I beg your pardon?
我的小妹妹，她把细节都说了...
My little sister. She wasadamant about every detail but...
就是忘了告诉我尺码，你介意吗?
neglected to tell me the size.Would you mind?
不，当然不会
Oh, no, of course not.
第一次有点挤
It's always a little snugthe first time.
也许你该退去戒指
Maybe you should takeoff your ring.
那是我的结婚戒指，我不能把它拿下来
It's my wedding ring,I never take it off.
那，就另一只手吧
The other hand, then.
不要系扣，你能看出来很合手的
No need to button it. You can seeit fits perfectly.
Darlington大人，你这个堕落的人
Lord Darlington,you depraved man.
你打算干什么啊?
What have you been up to?
别理他, Meg, 亲爱的他可是个大罪人
Ignore him, Meg, dear.He's a great sinner.
可却是个了不起的桥梁合伙人
But an excellent bridge partner.
要不我肯定会忍受不了他的
Or I would never tolerate him.
- 你们彼此认识了吗?- 在伦敦办事处的那年认识的
- Do you know each other?- The year I spent in the London office.
我跟你提过John但，你们已经认识了吧
I told you about John.But you've met.
- 没有，认识你很荣幸- 很荣幸，Windemere太太
- No. It's nice to meet you.- It's a pleasure, Mrs Windemere.
你太太正帮我给我母亲选手套
Your wife was helping me selectgloves for my mother.
- 你妹妹，你说的- 两个人的
- Your sister, you said.- Either one.
我们该一起用餐你们住哪?
We should have dinner.Where are you staying?
住Grand,但我们正在找别墅
The Grand, but we're tryingto find a villa.
在这个季节有点晚了，我警告过你的
So late in the season.I warned you.
我知道一个合适的
I know one that's available.
今年是狂野西部的竞选年吧?
Isn't it an election year inthe wild west?
谁说我参选了?
Who says I'm running?
- 真完美，太美了- 我提到鬼魂了吗?
- It's perfect. It's beaultiful.- Did I mention the ghost?
我能想到的都在这了我觉得自己象童话中的公主
I feel like a princessin a fairly tale.
你就是公主
You are a princess.
那是因为我嫁给了王子
That's because Imarried the prince.
我把她完全骗住了，可怜的女孩
I have her completely fooled,poor girl.
如果我能骗到一个象你太太一样漂亮的女孩我就不会仍是单身汉了
If I could fool a woman aspretty, I wouldn't be a bachelor.
- 看你让她不好意思了- 别傻了
- Now you've made her blush.- Don't be silly.
来看看画吧
Come and see the paintings.
走
Come on.
晚上好
Good evening.
Plymdale女士？
Lady Plymdale?
哦，她就是那个有大...
Oh, is she the onewith the big...
脚，著名的大脚可怜的老Plymdale
Feet. Enourmous feet.Poor old Plymdale.
- A, Q, K ，J- 真没面子
- Ace, Queen, King, Jack.- No honours.
不，John的游艇John的规矩
No, no, John's yacht,John's rules.
- 拿去- 谢谢你
- Have it.- Thank you.
大脚，浮桥
Huge feet. Pontoons.
如果期待能够修正，那就是她的浮桥了
If desire had an antidote, it wouldbe those pontoons of hers.
我想的都得病了
I grow ill thinking of then.
你离过多少次婚了, Tuppy?
How many times have youbeen divorced, Tuppy?
- 三次，四次? 我不会数了- 那是重婚
- Three, four? I've simply lost count.- That's bigamy.
重婚是有过多妻子
Bigamy is having one wifetoo many.
那是一夫一妻
So is monogamy
每个人都该有个合理的婚姻基础一个相互……
One should always have a properbasis for marriage. A mutual...
- 误解?- 没错
- Misunderstanding?- Exactly.
男人只有一个女人是不会快乐的
A man can't be happywith one woman.
只要不爱，男人跟任何女人都会快乐
A man can be happy with any woman.As long as he doesn't love her.
对于一个永不言婚的男人来说...
For a man who's never thoughtof getting married...
你知道的够多的
you seem to know an awfullot about it.
我对婚姻考虑甚为周详所以至今未婚
I've thought very seriously of marrying.That's why I'm still single.
听到了
Hear, hear.
我只是还没遇到合适的看Cecil, 还跟Edna在一起
I just haven't met the right woman.Look at Cecil, still with Edna.
一个人该在婚礼前大睁双眼...
One keeps one's eyes wide openbefore the wedding...
其后就要睁一眼闭一眼了
and half shut after.
- 就那么回事- 没错
- That's all there is to it.- Exactly.
我想结束了
I fancy raising the stakes.
哦，幸运的家伙
Oh, lucky blighter!
你看着不怎么开心啊
You don't look as ifyou're enjoying yourself.
哦，我开心，晚会很好
Oh, I am. It's a verynice party.
- 我能给你拿个饮品么?- 不了，谢谢，我不喝
- Can I get you a drink?- No, thank you. I don't drink.
你不喝?
You don't drink?
- 我看上去象个假正经的人吗?- 不，当然不是
- Do I seem like a prig?- No, of course not.
- 我就是那样被带大的- 在修道院吗?
- It's the way I was raised.- In a convent?
是我的Julia姑姑我父亲的姐姐
By my Aunt Julia.My father's sister.
我幼年丧母
My mother died when Iwas very little.
这是我有的她唯一的照片
It's the only picture Ihave of her.
我父亲从没再婚
My father never remarried.
她似她女儿般美貌
She's every bit as beaultifulas her daughter.
我冒犯你了吗?我是在恭维你呢
Have I offended you?I meant it as a compliment.
- 你过于恭维我了- 我会马上停止
- You pay me too many compliments.- I'll stop at once.
- 谢谢你- 你只要知道，我是真心的
- Thank you.- Just so you know, I meant every one.
你假装坏，但...
You pretend to be bad, but...
- 其实你不是- 没有好坏之分
- you're not really.- There is no good or bad.
人只有迷人和沉闷之分
People are either charmingor tedious.
如果我是后者，我真诚道歉
If I've been the latter,I sincerely apologize.
- 我希望我们能成朋友- 我们已经是了，对吧?
- I'd like us to become friends.- We already are, aren't we?
那就别奉承我或是说些愚蠢的恭维话
Not if you keep flattering me andpaying me silly compliments.
定义“愚蠢”
Define silly.
你得保证
I want your word.
我发现要想不食言就别乱保证
I find the best way to keep myword is never to give it.
看到漂亮女人永远都是一种荣幸
It's always a pleasureto see a pretty woman.
天气不错
Good day.
一定得是特别的东西...
It has to be somethingreally special...
是我妻子的生日
My wife's birthday.
这个非常特别
This is a very specialobject.
你觉得怎么样?
What do you think?
蓝宝石很衬你的眼睛
The sapphire matches your eyes.
是给我妻子的
It's for my wife.
男人可不该给妻子买珠宝
A man should never buy hiswife jewellery.
那是为什么?
And why is that?
那会让她猜测他会给情妇买什么
It makes her wonder whathe bought his mistress.
我妻子没什么可猜测的
My wife has nothing towonder about.
她是个幸运的女人
She's a lucky woman.
如果我是你妻子...
If I was your wife...
- 这才是我想要的- 一把扇子?
- this is what I'd want.- A fan?
不为鼓动空气，为了鼓动心灵
Not for stirring the air,for stirring the heart.
是经历百年...
For centuries...
男女间的性欲语言
an erotic language betweenmen an women.
如果女人把它这样放在胸前那意思是“我爱你”
If a woman placed it on her breastlike this, it meant "I love you".
"我几时能见你?"
"When can I see you?"
"等我"
"Wait for me."
"你可以亲吻我"
"You may kiss me."
"我们正被监视"
"We're being watched."
我被出卖了
I'm sold.
多少钱?
How much?
不，那个不是卖品
No, it's not for sale.
非卖品？
Not for sale.
那会伤透我妈妈的心
It would break mymom's heart.
我妈妈
My mama.
真金的
Real gold.
如果你倾囊而出谁给我买浓缩咖啡啊?
If you give him everything, who'sgoing to buy me an espresso?
我的后背啊
My back.
而且到处都是美国人
And Americans everywhere.
你根本不会知道他们国家正经历经济危机
You'd never know there was adepression in that country.
拜托，我晕倒前喝点东西吧
Please, something to drinkbefore I faint.
他们不是买东西，他们在掠夺
They don't shop, they pillage.
而且他们说话声音太吵
And they speak loudly.
难道他们整个民族都有听力障碍吗?
Could the entire nation behard of hearing?
可能是吃的东西有问题，也许?
Something in the diet, perhaps?
但是我们有美国朋友啊，妈妈
But we have Americanfriends, mama.
但他们不需要知道我们是怎么讲究他们的
They don't need to know whatwe say about them.
如果每个人都知道别人背后怎么讲究自己...
If everyone knew what everyonesaid of each other...
那人生在世不会有超过四个朋友了
there wouldn't be four friendsin the world.
我喜欢美国
I like America.
你找不到一个社会由荒蛮进入颓废
Name me another society that's gonefrom barbarism to decadence...
都不劳神经历文明时代
without bothering to create acivilization in between.
全拜美国人所赐
Tribute to American efficiency.
- Windemere先生在那- 他得加入我们
- There's Mr Windemere.- He must join us then.
他看不见你，妈妈
He can't see you, mama.
跟他一起的是谁?
Who's that with him?
好像是他妻子
Looks like his wife.
不，我看不是
No, I don't think it is.
我现在看不见了，他们进车里了
I can't see now.They're getting into the car.
如果她进车里肯定是他妻子
It must be the wife if she'sgetting into the car.
不是的
It wasn't her.
那我就得知道到底是谁
Then I must know who it is.
我觉得我们该管自己的事
I think we should mind ourown business.
我自己的事太无聊了
My own business bores me.
我更喜欢管别人闲事
I much prefer other people's.
可怜的Meg，她多可爱
Poor little Meg,she's so sweet.
而且她没妈妈
And the girl has no mother.
- 我想把她揽在怀里- 我曾有过类似想法
- I want to take her to my breast.- I had a similar thought.
我猜Windemere先生不会想听到这些
I don't suppose Mr Windemerewould be pleased to hear it.
神圣的赐福...
Merital bliss...
对两个人是巨大的负担, Tuppy
is a great burden to placeon two people, Tuppy.
有时第三者是摆脱负担的必需
Sometimes a third person isneeded to lighten the load.
看起来， Windemere先生是赞许你的
It would seem,Mr Windemere agrees with you.
我能猜出你干了什么
I can guess what you were doing.
给我买生日礼物?
Shopping for my birthday present?
我对了
I was right.
你买什么了?
What did you get?
什么也没买，你老得不配买礼物
Not a thing. You're too oldfor presents.
- 一个提示，一个小不点的提示- 你得等着瞧
- A hint. A tiny speck of a hint.- You'll have to wait and see.
- 香水?- 不，别猜了
- Perfume?- No, stop it.
一本诗集?
A book of poems?
一件套装?
A dress?
一个象女爵爷提的，用小爪子做扣的
A crocodile handbag like theone the Contessa has...
鳄鱼皮的手袋？
with the little claws hangingoff the bottom?
别猜了
No more guessing.
Robert?
保证我，我们不会落得跟那些老家伙一样的下场...
Promise we won't end up like thoseold married couples...
虽然在吃饭时面对面坐着但无话可谈
sitting opposite each other atdinner with nothing to say.
你，无话可谈?
You, with nothing to say?
我保证
I promise.
我们要一直彼此讲真话?
We'll always tell eachother the truth?
除了生日
Except around birthdays.
你很活跃啊在看什么书?
You're feisty.What have you been reading?
- 什么意思?- 没有，挺好
- What do you mean?- No, it's nice.
关上灯
Turn out the lights.
-可我想看你－拜托
- But I like to see you.- Please?
我都要了
I'll take them all.
- 你好，女士- 请原谅
- Good day, madam.- Excuse me.
我买了一件套装
I bought a suit.
正在改，给Margaret Windemere
It's being altered.For Margaret Windemere.
啊, Windemere太太请稍等
Ah, Mrs Windemere.One moment, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
请原谅你是美国人，对吧？
Forgive me.You're American, aren't you?
我从New York来，Erlynne太太
I'm from New York.Mrs Erlynne.
Rhode 岛，Windemere太太
Rhode Island.Mrs Windemere.
我需要点建议，真心话
I need an opinion from here.Now be honesty.
你会穿它吗?
Would you wear it?
这会让人失去想像力，是吧?
Well, it doesn't leave muchto the imagination, does it?
那要看有多少想像力，有些男人比其他的多些
That depends on the imagination.Some men have more than others.
我觉得肯定不够端庄
I suppose it's certainly immodest.
你觉得它粗俗吗?
Do you think it's vulgar?
有些人会那么想
Some people might.
你丈夫跟你一起来了吗?我需要一个男人的意见
Is your husband with you?I'd love a man's opinion.
我可以告诉你，他很保守
I can tell you.He's very conservative.
一个女人是不会了解她丈夫的
A woman doesn't knowher own husband.
哦，我了解 Robert我们都结婚快一年了
Oh, I know Robert.We've been married over a year.
一年？简直就跟一辈子似的
A year? Pratically forever.
给你，女士
Here it is, signora.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
多谢你，请再光顾
Thank you very much.Come back again to see us.
- 再见- 你不要帽子吗?
- Goodbye- You're not taking the hat?
颜色很合你，你不要吗?
The colour looks perfect on you.Don't you like it?
不，我没场合戴，周日并不上教堂
No, I've nowhere to wear it.It's not exactly church on sunday.
为什么?
Why not?
你能想像人们会怎么说吗?
Can you imagine whatpeople would say?
哦，如果我们总让别人左右我们...
Well, if we're always guided byother people's thoughts...
那还要自己的头脑干什么用呢?
what's the point ofhaving our own?
高兴人士你，Ewin太太
It was nice meeting you,Mrs Ewin.
- Erlynne.- Erlynne.
- Erlynne- Erlynne
她本来在一个小旅馆...
She was staying in a pensione...
现在她住在离俱乐部几分钟远的别墅里
now she's in a villa afew minutes from the club.
他在那
He's there.
我老是看见他
I can't help seeing him.
他整天来来去去
He comes and goes allhours of the day.
当然，在公开场合她总是跟其他男人在一起
Of course, in public, she'salways with other men.
她只穿最新的时装
She wears nothing butthe latest fashions.
肯定有某人给她很慷慨的资助
Somebody must be giving her a verygenerous allowance.
Silence!
安静
如果Tuppy还不清醒过来她就快把手伸进他口袋里了
And she'll have her hand in Tuppy'spocket next, if he doesn't wake up.
她不过是个公众的妓女
She's nothing better thana common prostitute.
Windemere太太不知道吗?
And Mrs Windemere has no idea?
根本不知道
None at all.
- 对不起- 她肯定在露台
- I'm sorry.- She must be on the terrace.
对不起，我可不想吓到你
I'm sorry, I didn'tmean to frighten you.
- 可你吓到我了- 没错，那是什么?
- Yes, you did.- Yes, you did. What's that?
我正准备我生日晚会的菜单
I'm making a menu formy birthday party.
龙虾的意大利文怎么说?
What's italian for lobster?
Aragosta
Aragosta.
很好，现在你把我搞的饿起来了
Very good. Now you've made me hungry.
放下吧，我们走所有人都在俱乐部吃饭
Leave it, come on. Everyone'slunching at the club.
好，我叫上Robert
Okay. I'll get Robert.
我以为你同意不往我家打电话?
I thought you agreed not tocall me at home?
你老带着丈夫，我怎么引诱你啊?
How can I seduce you if youalways bring your husband?
太慢了，走吧
Too slow. Come on.
好吧
All right.
好，我会在一小时到
Yes, I'll be there.In an hour.
好，一小时
Okay, in an hour.
该休息了，我们要去吃饭
It's quitting time.We're going to lunch.
不行，对不起
Can't, sorry.
- 你在工作吗?- 钱可不睡觉
- You're working?- Money never sleeps.
该死
Bugger!
付钱的工作吸引人
All paying jobs absorb...
也会使人堕落
and degrade the mind.
你没有付钱的工作
You never had a paying job.
我在休庭阶段
I rest my case.
有教养的休闲才是男人的去处
Cultivated leisure isman's true calling.
- 我要进城发电报- 我要等你
- I have to send some telegrams in town.- I'll wait for you.
我要一下午，我可不想浪费你一天（支票：给Erlynne太太，400元）
I'll be all afternoon.I don't want you to waste the day.
- 你介意吗, John?- 我介意?
- Do you mind, John?- Do I mind?
不，当然不会
No, of course not.
如果你非要护送那女人去看歌剧别跟我们坐一起
If you have to escort that woman tothe opera, please don't sit with us.
想想Alessandra
Think of Alessandra.
Erlynne 太太有自己的座位
Mrs Erlynne has her own seats.
谁付的钱?
Who pays for them?
她叔叔刚死，有些进项
Her uncle just died.She's come into some money.
Windemere先生的拜访呢?
And Mr Windemere's visits?
他当然是在运作她的投资了
He's managing her investments,of course.
你太爱嚼舌根了
You're so fond of gossip.
根本没给真相一个穿裤子的机会
You don't give the truth a chanceto put its pants on.
亲爱的Tuppy，没穿裤子的不是真相
It's not the truth that's going withoutpants, dear Tuppy.
你介意别抽烟吗?
Would you mind not smoking?
歌剧让我感觉太浪漫了
Opera makes me feel so romantic.
歌唱真是无聊之极
Anything too stupid to besaid is sung.
有什么浪漫的?
How's that romantic?
而且女人也都太肉感了
And the women arealways so fleshy!
对不起，那是我的脚
Excuse me, that's my foot.
就在那吗?
Right over here?
我怎么跟你说的？
What did I tell you?
别那样，孩子
Stop, boy!
沼泽里的炸凤尾鱼配蛤喇美味
Fried anchovies and clamsin a bog. Delicious.
小心，很烫
Careful, it's hot.
你跟Robert说我们去俱乐部
You told Robert we weregoing to the club.
我方向感极差
I have a very poor senseof direction.
你的礼貌才差
You have a very poor senseof decorum.
我从不用那个字，把握不好意思
I never use that word.I'm not sure what it means.
- 在俱乐部就得跟其他人在一起- 说对了
- At the club we'd be with other people.- You're right.
而我们在这里，在阳光里...
Here we are,in the sunshine...
吃着刚从船上打来的鱼...
eating fish, literallyjust off the boat...
代替了在Tubby大人和光彩照人的 Cecil中间挤着……
when we could be squashed between LordTubby and Cecil the Scintillating...
听他们抱怨自己的消化病
listening to one or theother gripe about his digestion...
同时混杂着女爵爷哀号……
while the Contessa, in acounter-medley, wails that...
Alessandra比关心自己...
Alessandra cares more for...
还更关心蓝腹鸟交配习惯...
the mating habits of theblue bellied finch...
Plymdale寡妇转着怪异的眼睛...
than those of her own species,and the widow Plymdale...
死盯着别人的裤子
bats her eyes logingly everypassing pair of trou.
那是我看书时打发的时光
All of which is time wellspent in my book.
所以，是的，我接受你的意见
So, yes, I take your point.
我无法争辩，在俱乐部我们得跟其他人一起
I can't argue. At the club, we'dbe with other people.
害怕我们被发现吗?
Afraid we'll be seen?
给人嚼舌根?
Set the chins wagging?
你知道我发现比被人嚼舌根更可怕的是什么?
Do you know what I findworse than being talked about?
根本不被人谈起
Not being talked about at all.
Erlynne太太在楼上见你
Mrs Erlynne will see you upstairs.
在她卧室
In her bedroom.
谢谢，我不会久呆
Thank you. I won't be long.
"我不会久呆"
"I won't be long."
这很贵
This is expensive.
- 只给你最好的- 我知道，是我付的钱
- Nothing but the best for you.- I know, I paid for it.
都在那了
Well, there is that.
我们该这么早就喝酒吗?
Should we be drinking thisearly in the day?
世界上的某地现在很晚了
Well, somewhere in the worldit's very late.
我不想让你觉得这样成习惯了
I don't want you thinkingI make a habit of this.
那是你看上去内疚的原因吗?
Is that why you look so guilty?
我不喜欢跟她说谎
I don't like lying to her.
我得走了，她只是去吃饭
I should go.She's only gone to lunch.
这是我现在所有的现金
This is all the cashI have right now.
我会给你建个账号
I'll set you up with an account.
你就可以直接提取了
You can draw on it directly.
我遇到Meg了
I met Meg.
是个巧遇
It was by chance.
没事的，她不知道我是谁
It's all right,she had no idea who I was.
你跟她说话了吗?
You spoke to her?
对，很短，她很漂亮
Yes, for a minute.She's very pretty.
你们俩怎么遇上的?是一见钟情吗?
How did you two meet?Was it love at first sight?
我得走了
I have to go.
我好奇，很自然的
I'm curious. It's only natural.
这些问题没意义
There's no pointto these questions.
- 你爱她吗?- 很爱
- Do you love her?- Very much.
我宁可断臂也不想让Meg受伤
I'd rather cut off my armthan see Meg hurt.
你是在保护她还是保护你的名声?
Are you protecting her oryour reputation?
你对我一无所知
You don't know me at all.
他在你们的新婚之夜也工作吗?
Did he work on yourwedding night?
他很尽责，我为此而敬重他
He's very conscientiousand I respect him for it.
假设不是因为工作，假设他有情妇
Suppose it wasn't work,suppose he had a mistress.
哦，那我可不敬重了
Well, I couldn't respect that.
一旦妻子遭背叛...
Once a wife's been betrayed...
她就有依样做的理由
she has the freedom todo likewise.
不，那岂不让她跟那丈夫一样坏了吗?
No, that would make her as badas her husband, wouldn't it?
现代婚姻因彼此欺骗而兴旺
Modern marriage thrives onmutual deception.
我们彼此完全忠诚
We are completely honestwith each other.
你该以他为榜样
You should makehim your model.
我正打算，从现在开始
I intend to.From this moment on.
你不喜欢吗?
Don't you like it?
哦，我给Robert留着，他喜欢无花果
Oh, I'm saving it for Robert.He loves figs.
那吃我的吧
Share mine, then.
我们能去电报局吗?
Can we go to thetelegraph office?
他可能还没吃东西呢
He probably hasn't eaten.
Alberto? Fabrizio?
哦，他叫什么?
Oh, what's his name?
Mario?
酒保
Barman.
威士忌
Whisky.
另外, 你的Erlynne太太完全没有原则
And another thing, your Mrs Erlynnehas no principles at all.
我喜欢人甚于原则
I like people more than principles.
没原则的人就更好了
And people without principles,even better.
但是Augustus大人她只是要你的钱啊
But Lord Augustus, she onlywants you for your money.
她干嘛不能？那是我最好的资产
Now why shouldn't she?It's my best asset.
又老又胖，完全无脑
Old-ish, fat-ish,absolutely no brain...
成堆的钞票
heaps and heaps of banknotes.
并不需要贬低自己，Tuppy
No need toput yourself down, Tuppy.
让你的朋友们来嘛
Your friends can always do that.
在码头，一起徘徊，跟你一样美……
Down by the marina, strolling along,pretty as you please...
猜我看见谁跟Darlington大人在一起?
guess who I saw withLord Darlington?
他们今天没看见他
They haven't seen him today.
你知道我丈夫在哪吗?
Do you know wheremy husband is?
我以为他跟你一起走了，女士
I thought he leftafter you, signora.
Robert?
午饭怎样?
How was lunch?
我们去电报局了，你去哪了?
We went to the telegraph office.Where were you?
我们也许刚巧错过了
Well, we must have justmissed each other.
现在我看见叔叔了他跟那美国女人在一起
Now I see uncle.He's with the american woman.
口红过多，衣服过少
Too much rouge and notenough clothing.
她使尽招数引诱那可怜的男人
She's appealing to the worstin the poor man.
那是女人的拿手好戏
It's what women do best.
我听说她离开New York连酒店的帐都没付
I heard she left New Yorkwithout paying her hotel bill.
真是个丑闻
Quite a scandal.
- 谁? 你认识的人吗?- 是个你不想认识的人
- Who? Someone you know?- Someone you don't want to know.
不，Steer Clear
No. Steer clear.
她就是跟Augustus大人在一起的
She's the onewith Lord Augustus.
你已经认识Erlynne太太了，是吧？
You've met Mrs Erlynne,haven't you?
- 没有.- 可我看见你了
- No.- But I've seen you.
哦，那是你的脚吗?
Oh, was that your foot?
你到哪去找合脚的鞋啊?
Wherever do you findshoes to fit?
我的脚跟我身体其他部分很成比例
My feet are in perfect proportionto the rest of me.
哦，是的，当然
Oh, yes, of course.
尽管他们有在奇特的地方出现的习惯
Though they have a habit of findingthemselves in peculiar places.
那些人在盯着我们看呢
Those people arestaring right at us.
谁?
Who?
别理会他们
Don't worry about them.
那是我哥哥的妻子和她的朋友Plymdale女士
It's my brother's wife andher friend, Lady Plymdale.
Plymdale大人去年死了，肝，我想
Lord Plymdale passed onlast year. Liver, I think.
- 可怜的女人- 哦，是的，很悲惨
- Poor woman.- Oh, yes, very sad.
因为伤心，她的头发越发的金色了
Her hair turned quitegold with grief.
Erlynne, 对了，她有了一些进项
Erlynne, that's right.She came into some money.
- 我为她管理投资- 是遗产吧，我猜?
- I made an investment for her.- An inheritance, I suppose?
商店里的女人，我告诉过你的，记得吗?
The woman in the shop.I told you, remember?
套装?
The dress?
不，后背，几乎没有前片你什么都能看见
No, back and almost no front.You could see everything.
很不像样
It was indecent.
你只是不习惯意大利时装而已
You're just not used toItalian fashions, that's all.
我觉得你妻子挺合拍的
No, I'm sure your wife ison the mark.
Erlynne太太是个声名狼藉的无耻女人
Mrs Erlynne is anotorious Jezebel.
那是诽谤，如果你不收回，我不会重复
That's a slanderous statement. If youcan't back it up, I wouldn't repeat it.
Robert总是给不随便评价他人的
Robert always gives everybodythe benefit of the doubt.
对不起，我只是不喜欢流言
I'm sorry, I just don't like gossip.
流言没什么，这是口味低下的布道
Gossip's all right, it's themoralising that's in poor taste.
她看上我了，你该懂我意思
She's got her eye on me,if you know what I mean.
所以我根本不担心他们说什么不过是囊中之物吧了
So I wouldn't worry about what theysay, it's all cats in a bag.
怎么了，他们怎么说我的？
Why, what do they say about me?
说我是荡妇?
That I'm a wanton woman?
厚颜无耻，背景复杂
Brazen - with a past.
一个厚颜无耻的女人，哦，我的天啊
A brazen woman.Oh, dear.
由我陪伴的你才真是厚颜无耻呢
You're very brazen yourselfto be seen in my company.
我也有个复杂的背景啊
I've got a bit of a pastmyself you know.
结婚离婚了两次
Married and divorced twice.
每个经历都有价值
Every experience is of value andwhatever you say...
无论你怎么讲究婚姻都肯定是有价值的
about marriage it certainlyis an experience.
当人们讲究经历的时候...
People call somethingan experience...
他们多半说的是错误
They usually meanit was a mistake.
我无任同意
I couldn't agree more.
我们都在储藏间里藏着几具骷髅
We've all got a couple ofskeletons in the closet.
如果他们要喋喋不休还不如干脆跳舞
If they're going to rattle,they may as well dance.
你完全正确
You're absolutely right.
只要有人赞同我我一定错了
Whenever anyone agrees with me,I'm sure I must be wrong.
你喜欢作最后一个剩下的人，是吧?
You like to be theodd man out, do you?
我从来就不能理解女人
I'll never understand women.
女人不需要人理解，只需要人爱
Women don't want to be understood,they want to be loved.
你这就大错了
You're dead wrong on that.
你真善解人意
You're very understanding.
戴丁香花的女人，你认识吗?
That girl in lilac,do you know her?
哦，是的，那是Robert的妻子
Oh, yes, it's Robert's wife.
很可爱，很迷人
All lovey-dovey,very charming.
我希望她别再盯着我了
I wish she'd stop staring at me.
她没有
She isn't at all.
那些女人肯定在给她进言呢
Those women must begiving her an earful.
- 你别介意- 按照惯例，我没有
- You mustn't mind.- I don't, as a rule.
你看，这很乏味，我都不能喘气了
Look, it's terribly stuffy in here,I can hardly breathe.
我们走吧，你介意吗？
Shall we go? Would you mind?
我根本一点都不介意
I can't think of anythingI'd mind less.
好
Good.
我不敢相信，她钓上他了
I can't believe it - she's got him!
可怜的Tuppy
Poor Tuppy.
我叫个出租车吧?
Shall I get a taxi?
- 可以走路吗?- 为何不呢
- Could we walk?- Why not.
漂亮的城市
Beautiful city.
罗马人叫它"妖妇之城"
The Romans call it"The Land of the Sirens..."
出自荷马的《奥德赛》
from Homer's Odyssey.
真的吗?你真聪明
Is that so? Aren't you clever?
- 我在哪里读到的- 我也喜欢阅读
- I read it somewhere.- I like a good read myself.
别太累，我不想影响自然的无知
Nothing too laborious. I don't wantto tamper with natural ignorance.
- 是快乐的钥匙- 你真那么想吗?
- It's the key to happiness.- Do you really think so?
绝对是，健康，很重要...
Absolutely. Good health,it's important, but...
无知是钥匙，太多知识你就被限制住了
ignorance is the key. Too muchknowledge and you're doomed.
嗯，到了
Well, here we are.
你都不邀请我进睡前酒吗?
Aren't you going to invite mein for a nightcap?
传说中的妖妇是半人半魔
The sirens were said to behalf woman, half monster.
她们用歌声引诱水手
They lured the sailors withtheir songs.
船只触礁，水手溺水
The ships crashed on therocks and the men all drowned.
哦，进去吧，你再多告诉我一些
Oh, let's go in. You can tell memore about it.
可怜的Plymdale女士,我觉得她是真喜欢Tuppy
Poor Lady Plymdale, I think shereally likes Tuppy.
- 你觉得他们去哪里了?- 谁?
- Where do you suppose they went?- Who?
Tuppy 和Erlynne太太
Tuppy and Mrs Erlynne.
可能回她住所了
Probably back to her apartment.
可能
Probably.
你觉得他会邀请她参加我的舞会吗?
Do you think he'll inviteher to my party?
我会确保他不能
I'll make sure he doesn't.
- 别太刻薄了- 不，当然不会
- Well, don't be mean about it.- No, of course not.
只是我不想让任何人尴尬，明白吗?
It's just I don't want anyoneto be uncomfortable, you know?
那样的事会令局面很难受
Someone like that makesthings awkward.
你就说是个小舞会，只是些朋友而已
You can say it's a small party.Private, just friends.
- 没有投资人- 好
- No investors.- All right.
那不只是女孩的流言，JohnDarlington 知道所有情况
It's not just girl gossip. JohnDarlington knows all abou it.
他说她的朋友是个已婚男人
He said her friend isa married man.
真令人厌恶
It's disgusting.
你知道吗，人们喜欢听自己讲话
You know what, people like tohear themselves talk.
- 你干嘛要坚持为她辩护?- 我没替她辩护
- Why do you insist on defending her?- I'm not defending her.
你有
Yes, you are.
我们别说了
Let's drop it.
只是……你该替她管理投资吗?
It's just... Should yoube helping her invest?
所有人都知道她钱的来路
Everyone knows how shecame into the money.
新话题
New topic.
闭眼
Close your eyes.
- Robert?- 闭眼
- Robert?- Close your eyes.
已经过午夜了生日快乐
It's after midnight.Happy birthday.
- 真美- 你喜欢吗?
- It's beautiful.- Do you like it?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我爱你- 我也爱你
- I love you.- I love you, too.
哦，天啊
Oh, my!
- 谢谢- 别提了
- Thank you.- Don't mention it.
你喜欢吗?
You like it?
食物是岩石...
Food is the rock...
由我们创造
on which we build.
没有爱象食物一样纯洁而简单
No love is pure and simpleas the love of food.
爱少有纯洁，Augustus大人而且从不简单
Love is rarely pure, Lord Augustus.And never simple.
我不认为你曾爱过，Erlynne太太
I don't think you've beenin love, Mrs Erlynne.
你可以假称我Stella...
You may presumeto call me Stella...
但别假装你知道我的心
but don't presumeto know my heart.
根据你的情报，我永远都在恋爱
For your information,I'm always in love.
好，出色的态度，而且你很美
Good. Excellent attitude.And you're beautiful.
也精明，比我精明，我希望……
Smart, too. Smarter than me,I expect, but...
希望没说太多
that's not saying much,I'm afraid.
不，我觉得如果跟你结婚我会很好的
No, I think I'll do very wellto marry you.
多实际啊
How very practical.
我开始过太多不涉及情感的浪漫了
I've begun too many romancesout of sentiment.
最终都以结算为结局
They always end in settlement.
我可以整夜听你倾诉Augustus大人
I could listen to you all night,Lord Augustus.
请叫我Tuppy
Tuppy, please.
你会考虑我的提议吗?
You'll think about my offer?
男人不跟我这样的女人结婚的
Men don't marry women like me.
那是因为没有你这样的女人
There aren't any women like you.
至少我认识的人里面没有我遇到可以分享的了
At least, not among the womenI've met, and I've met my share.
我曾结婚，但不喜欢
I was married - I didn't take to it.
人会变，你会感受到不同的
People change. You mightfeel differently.
当我想到的时候我想到
When I think of it, I thinkof a room...
一个不能开窗的房间
where you can't open a window.
因为没有窗户
Where there is no window.
每天醒来，你发现房间又变小了
Every day you wake upand the room is smaller.
你不会注意，开始不会逐渐发生
You don't notice, not at first.It happens slowly.
一点点的
In inches.
然后某天早晨你睁眼发现...
Then one morning,you open your eyes...
房间已经小的...
and the room is so small...
你无法腾挪了
you can't move.
无法呼吸
You can't take a breath.
你不得不逃走
You have to get out.
你什么事都无法想
You can't think of anything else.
什么人都无法想
Or anyone else.
你只是嫁错了人
You married the wrong man,that's all.
他娶错了人
He married the wrong woman.
很晚了
It's late.
该上床了
It's time for bed.
睡觉
Sleep.
"偶然的梦境"
"...Perchance to dream".
是吟游诗人，你知道我自己也读过点书的
That's the bard, you know.I'm a bit of a reader myself.
照你说的，晚安，Tuppy
So you said. Goodnight, Tuppy.
我讨厌烟草味
I hate the taste of tobacco.
好，就这样
Well - that's it then.
我戒了，当场
I quit. On the spot.
我还能告诉你什么?
What else can I tell you?
我是个非常富有的人，你知道
I'm a very rich man, you know.
你是个非常好的人
You're a very nice man.
上床吧
Go to bed.
你知道，我很高兴戒烟了
You know, I'm glad I quit.
肮脏的习惯，真的
Filthy habit, really.
晚安
Goodnight.
是驯狮人或只是普通的小丑?
Is there going to be a lion tamer,or is it just the usual clowns?
Robert害怕会下雨呢
Robert was afraid it might rain.
我本来只想几个人吃饭但他说你一生只得一次21岁
I just wanted a few people for dinnerbut he said you are only 21 once.
我认识很多女人，按照她们的记录年年都过35
I know plenty of women who, of theirown accord, turn 35 year after year.
我肯定你可以21岁很多年
I'm sure you can be 21 as many times.
我觉得对于岁数撒谎很蠢
I think it's silly to lie about your age.
- 你没有补偿的恶习- 我希望没有
- You have no redeeming vices.- I hope not.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
邀请信上写了不要礼物
The invitation said no gifts.
所以我现在把它带来了
That's why I brought it now.
这太贵了，我知道你没什么意思...
It's too expensive. I know youdon't mean anything by it, but...
但看上去不对
it wouldn't look right.
金子衬什么都行，戴上就是了不需要人知道
Gold looks right with everything.Just wear it. No-one has to know.
我知道
I'd know.
我可意味深长
I do mean something by it.
- 拜托...- 这是友谊的礼物, Maggie
- Please...- It's a gift of friendship, Maggie.
如果你拒绝就太伤我了
You'll hurt me deeply if you refuse.
看看你现在逼的我
Now look what you've made me do.
一点真诚会成为很危险的事
A little sincerity can be a verydangerous thing.
再来点就致命了
Any more could be fatal.
在我死在你露台上前赶紧把这该死的玩艺接过去吧
Just take the damn thing beforeI die and ruin your terrace.
很美，谢谢你
It's very pretty. Thank you.
Robert在哪? 又发电报去了吗？
Where's Robert? Off sendinganother telegram?
女主人，花匠在等着拿工钱
Signora, the florist is waitingfor his money.
我得跟Windemere先生拿
I'll have to get it fromMr Windemere.
他能呆会儿再来吗?
Can he come back later?
Robert 在办公室不是有支票本吗？
Has Robert a cheque-bookin his office?
- 你能在账户签单吗?- 啊，是的，当然
- Can you sign on the account?- Ah, yes, of course.
让他等一下我们今晚见了
Tell him to wait.I'll see you tonight.
人们并不总象我们希望的那样守规矩
People don't always behavethe way we expect.
其实正相反，事实是我不希望看到你受伤
Just the opposite. The truth is Idon't want to see you hurt.
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
这些日子你或许需要个朋友
You may need a friendone of these days.
当你需要的时候，我在这里你会记得吗?
When you do, I'm here.Will you remember that?
是，当然
Yes, of course.
我尽快赶来了
I came as quickly as I could.
我们都很悲伤
We're all so distressed over it.
可你不该太责备自己了
But you mustn't take it personally.
Erlynne太太是那种...
Mrs Erlynne is one ofthose women...
火焰吸引蜜蜂一样吸引男人的女人
that attract men like abee to a flame.
- 是飞蛾- 飞蛾吸引蜜蜂
- A moth.- Bee to a moth.
一定有其他解释
There must be someother explanation.
我有个主意－咱们去散步好吗?
I have an idea - shallwe go for a walk?
当婚姻没有爱时会有无婚姻的爱
When there's marriage without love,there'll be love without marriage.
但Robert和我是因爱而结合的...
But Robert and I marriedfor love...
当然，我也曾是的
Of course. And so did I.
但当热情逝去后...
But before the year was over...
Benito开始摆弄各式衬裙
Benito was lifting all kindsof petticoats.
我不得已辞去了最好的女佣
I had to dismiss my best maid.
不，我想起来了
No, no, I remember.
我把她送给了我的表亲
I passed her on tomy cousin.
她丈夫很短视，我觉得
Her husband was soshort-sighted, I thought.
他好像是循着气味查的
But he navigated by scent,it seems.
真不幸
So unfortunate.
相信我，这我们都经历过
Believe me, darling,it happens to us all.
不死的爱就象你别墅里的鬼魂
Undying love is like theghost in your villa.
人们都谈论...
Everybody talks about it...
但试试去找一个得到的人吧
but try and find one personwho has seen it.
- 你能帮我个忙吗?- 任何事
- Can I ask you a favour?- Anything at all.
关于Erlynne太太...
About, Mrs Erlynne...
很聪明的女人
Very clever woman.
她昨晚把我扔出来了
She threw me out last night.
知道了我有多蠢知道的跟我自己一样清楚
Knows what a fool I am.Knows it as well as I do myself.
她会在这跟我碰面喝茶
She's meeting me herefor tea, though.
能跟一个完全理解我的女人走到一起真是太棒了
It's a great thing to come across awoman who thoroughly understands me.
今晚别带她到我们的舞会你会介意吗?
Would you mind not bringingher to our party tonight?
这是你要的帮忙吗?
That's the favour?
Meg 觉得那样会使事情变的不舒服
Meg feels it might makethings awkward.
那么是真的喽?
So it's true, then?
我不相信，你不是那个类型
I don't believe it.You don't seem the type.
尽管我会说Erlynne太太实在迷人难以抗拒，但是……
Though I will say Mrs Erlynne's damnfascinating. Hard to resist, but...
你不是认真的，对吧?
You're not serious, are you?
我警告你，你得跟我决斗才能抢她
I warn you, you'll have tofight me for her.
而我可是个坠入爱河的男人
And I'm a man in love.
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
这边请，Erlynne太太
This ways, Mrs Erlynne.
- 多谢- 不客气
- Thanks.- You're welcome.
- 跟我来- 你往哪里带我?
- Come with me.- Where are you taking me?
- 放开我的手- 我非跟你谈谈不可
- Let go of my arm.- I have to talk to you.
我要见Augustos大人
I'm meeting Lord Augustos.
你马上得离开Amalfi
You must leave Amalfi at once.
去哪?你已经替我付了一个季的租金
And go where? You've paid myrent here for the season.
我会付其他地方的帐我要你上明天第一班飞机
I'll pay it somewhere else. I wantyou on the first plane out tomorrow.
- 我不理解- 人们在谈论
- I don't understand.- People are talking.
我们
About us.
我不觉得可笑
I don't see the humour.
在这里，埋葬一个秘密会冒出另一个假的吗？
Bury a real secret anda false one pops up in its place?
你得承认确实这么荒谬
There's a certain irony,you have to admit.
我不想走，在这挺高兴的
I'm not ready to leave.I'm enjoying myself here.
我恳求你
I'm begging you.
想想Meg，如果她知道你是她妈妈...
Think of Meg. If she knew thatyou were her mother...
那会毁灭她的
it would destroy her.
Meg, 高尚的Windemeres?
Meg, of the magnificentWindemeres?
家族丑闻对一个有抱负的政治家是不健康的
Family scandal is unhealthyfor aspiring politicians.
我不是这屋里唯一一个爱管闲事的人
I'm not the only pragmatistin this room.
爱管闲事? 20年，音讯全无
Pragmatist? Twenty years,and not a word.
当她嫁入豪门时你倒出现了
You turn up when she marriesa man with money.
你管那叫爱管闲事？我有更好的形容方法
You call that pragmatism?I can think of other words.
你想伤害我的感情吗?
Are you trying to hurtmy feelings?
你有感情吗？那是不能买卖的
Do you have any? That can'tbe purchased, I mean.
多少钱，能让你坐上头班机走开?
How much - to get youon the first flight out?
我觉得每次他吻我都是不洁的
I feel every time he'skissed me it's filthy.
我们在一起的每分钟都是谎言
A lie, every minute we'vebeen together.
他怎么能呢?
How could he?
每个男人生来都说实话但死时都是骗子
Every man is born truthfuland every man dies a liar.
现在，无论你做什么都不能引人注目
Now, whatever you do, youmustn't make a scene.
太令人不快而且也浪费你的精力
It's too unpleasant.And you waste your energy.
当然不会
No, of course not. I wouldn't.
哭是平庸女人的庇护所
Crying is the refugeof plain women.
漂亮女人去购物
Pretty women go shopping.
上那班飞机我会把现金奉上
Be on that plane.I'll send the cash.
我没听错吧?
Did I hear you correctly?
Meg Windemere 是你的女儿?
That Meg Windemere isyour daughter?
我女儿?
My daughter?
Robert的妻子?
Robert's wife?
你怎么敢
How dare you.
她至少有20岁了，她的妈妈?
She must be twenty at least.Her mother?
我真的看上去有那么老吗?
Do I look as old as all that?
当然不是
Of course not.
我一定是在打盹
I must have nodded off.
你困了，回去接着睡吧
You were dozing.Go back to sleep.
快点
Come on.
今晚不谈生意，我们改天再谈
No business tonight.We can talk another day.
-高兴见到你-晚会真好
- Good to see you.- Lovely party.
再来点香槟
More champagne.
欢迎，好好玩
Welcome.Have a great party.
- 晚上好，Dumby先生- 哦，晚上好，Stutfield太太
- Good evening, Mr Dumby.- Oh, good evening, Mrs Stutfield.
这一季最后的晚会了吧
Last party of the season,I suppose.
- 真令人愉快，是吧?- 非常令人愉快
- It's been delightful, hasn't it?- Quite delightful.
晚上好，这里，是本季最后的晚会了
Good evening. Here it is,the last party of the season.
我猜也是，尽管是个闷人的季节是吧？
I suppose so. It's been a very dullseason, though, hasn't it?
闷人，是啊，很闷
Dull. Yes, terribly dull.
－晚安, Cecil- 你好, Dumby
- Evening, Cecil.- Hello, Dumby.
我希望这是本季最后的晚会了
I suppose this'll be the lastparty of the season.
肯定不是，至少还会有两个
Surely not. Probablybe two more at least.
我今天做了个怪透了的梦
I had the oddest dream today.
刚刚想起了一小部分...
A bit of it has justcome back to me...
我们喝什么呢?
So what are we drinking?
- 生日女郎在哪里?- 正在变形
- Where's the birthday girl?- Transforming herself.
香肠和女人
Sausages and women.
如果你想享受她们...
If you want to enjoy theexperience...
千万别看过程
never watch thepreparation of either.
- 那是新的吗?- 刚出盒，你喜欢吗?
- Is that new?- Just out of the box. Do you like it?
你会有点冷，我给你拿个披肩吧
You might be a little cold.I'll get you a wrap.
毁掉线条吗，你朋友没教你意大利时装吗?
And spoil the lines? Didn't your friendteach you about Italian fashion?
我朋友?
My friend?
我看见支票了，少来...
I saw the cheques. Don't even...
Plymdale女士, 你来真好
Lady Plymdale, so good ofyou to come.
再要一杯香槟吗?
Do you want another glass ofchampagne?
我俩都来点吧
Let's get us both some.
你怎么给我问安?
Why don't you ask me how I am?
我喜欢人给我问安
I like people to ask.
表示对我健康的普遍关心
It shows a widespreadinterest in my health.
你不会知道那让人多舒服
And you can't imagine howcomforting that is.
晚会不错
Lovely party.
- 你好, Cecil?- 一点都不好
- How are you, Cecil?- Oh, not well at all.
我希望Alessandra...
I'd like Alessandra...
to know Mr. Hopperfrom Australia.
认识一下从澳洲来的Hopper先生
- 你可以介绍一下吗?- 请容我一点时间好吗?
- Would you introduce her?- Would you just excuse me for a moment?
跟Windemere先生走谢谢
Go with Mr Windemere.Thank you.
她是我最小的，我会想她的
She's my last, you know.I will miss her.
但是在她们开始攻击你之前...
But it's best to get them outof the nest...
还是把她们从巢里赶走吧
before they turn on you.
女孩最初是爱妈妈的但长大后就会评价你
Girls begin by loving their mothers.But as they grow they judge us.
很少会宽容
Rarely do they forgive us.
哦，可怜的傻子就是学不会
Oh, poor fool.He'll never learn.
那个傻子？别让我选
Which fool?Don't make me choose.
Tuppy,他把Erlynne太太带来了
Tuppy,he's brought Mrs Erlynne.
所有女人都会怠慢她
All the women will snub her.
她跟男人在一起没准会有点运气
She may have betterluck with the men.
那是因为男人...
It is because of men...
女人才不信任女人
that women distrust other women.
女人不信女人,男人也不信女人...
Women don't trust women,men don't trust women...
没人相信女人
no-one trusts women.
就是这个联合了印度教和天主教
It's what binds the Hinduand the Catholic.
我知道我发过誓但我必需说你今晚真美
I know I promised, but I must tellyou how beautiful you look tonight.
好吧，如果你非说就说吧
Well, if you must, you must.
请原谅，我在找其他人
I beg your pardon, I waslooking for someone else.
而你找到了我
Well, you found me.
Erlynne太太
Mrs Erlynne.
我可以叫你Stella吗？
May I call you Stella?
Augustus大人给我拿香槟去了
Lord Augustus is gettingme champagne.
你和我可以交换恩宠
You and I can trade favours.
很诱人，但算了
Tempting, but no.
我宁愿他不会看到月光下的我们或许会令他误解
I'd rather he didn't see us under themoonlight. He might misunderstand.
听我说
Hear me out.
Windemere财富胜过Tuppy
Windemere's fortune exceeds Tuppy's.
干嘛现在换马?
Why change horses now?
你得到所要的，Meg也自由了
You can have waht youwant and Meg's free.
自由?
Free?
她没有离开他的勇气
She hasn't the courage to leave him.
但如果明确了他跟你在一起...
But if it's clear to her thathe's with you...
他没有
He's not.
你买的谣言不可靠，赶紧去退款吧
You've been buying idle gossip.You should get a refund.
请原谅
Excuse me.
我非邀请她不可, Dumby
I had to invite her, Dumby.
问题是，她变了你可以从她眼睛里看出来
The point is, she's a changed woman.You can see it in her eyes.
你以为你要是穷她会看你一眼吗?
Do you think she'd look atyou if you were poor?
那你以为如果她丑我会看她吗?
Do you think I'd look at herif she were ugly?
公平是公平，互利互惠
Fair's fair, exchange ratesand so forth.
我知道她有点这有点那...
I know she's had her thisand her that, but...
但如果男人能有过去...
if a man can toleratehis own past...
他妻子干嘛不能有?而且肯出钱...
Why not a past in his wife?At any rate...
什么都能擦干净重新开始
it's wipe the slate.Clean start.
她和我……我们可以互相理解
She and I, we...understand each other.
你知道他们怎么说
And you know what they say.
每个圣人都有个过去而每个罪人都有个未来
Every saint has past,every sinner has a future.
如果她肯要，我想向她求婚
I'm going to ask her to marryme if she'll have me.
你知道人们为什么称之为圣坛, Tuppy?
You know why they call itan altar, Tuppy?
因为那里以人为祭祀
It's where they makehuman sacrifices.
我今天梦到 Erlynne太太
I had a dream aboutMrs Erlynne today.
是吗...
Yes, well...
你是情不自禁吧...
you couldn't help it,I suppose. She...
她真了不起
she is quite the woman.
但以后……
But in future...
还是请梦别人去吧
please try to dream ofsomeone else.
你不觉得自己喝够了吗?
Don't you think you'vehad enough?
- 晚会很好- 谢谢赏光
- Lovely party.- Thanks for coming.
Meg?
我得去换衣服
I have to change.
- 你看见她了吗?- 没有
- Did you see her?- Don't.
你很可爱
You're lovely.
她那岁数的女人穿真荒唐
It's ridiculous on a woman at her age.
你干嘛不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
你说过你是我的朋友
You said you were my friend.
男女之间无法成朋友
Men and women can't be friends.
- Meg?- 不
- Meg?- No.
你能跟他在一起吗?
Can you stay with him?
你今晚能跟他上床吗?
Can you get into bedwith him tonight?
明晚?以后呢？
Tomorrow night?Nights after that?
你自己说的，男人背叛妻子不可原谅
You said yourself, there's noforgiving a man who betrays his wife.
你怎么选?
What will you choose?
一个虚伪可耻的婚姻还是一个没有妥协的真我？
A false degrading marriage, or yourown true self, free of compromise?
我对你一见钟情，这是真的
I've loved you from the beginning.It's the truth.
你在手套店抽出手来的那刻我想“就是她了”
Moment you held out your hand to me inthe glove shop, I thought 'there she is".
那时，我是否该不加停留的离去呢?
And then, suppose I'd walkedby without stopping?
只那样一想
Just the thought of it.
至今我从未爱过
I've never loved anyone until now.
停
Stop.
John?
对不起，我不想吓你
I'm sorry, I didn't meanto startle you.
我在找Meg，你看见她了吗？
I'm looking for Meg. If you see her,it's important.
你排队了吗?
Have you had a row?
一个小舞会
A little misunderstanding.
看看酒吧
Try the bar.
Tuppy为她戒烟了
Tuppy's given up smokes for her.
女人
Women.
Women 给我们向上的灵感
Women inspire us to great things.
却又不明所以地阻止我们实施
Then somehow prevent usfrom doing any of them.
他向她求婚了
He's proposing to her.
该是他第三次上圣坛了
It will be his third time up the aisle.
希望是个制胜之举， Dumby
Hope trumps experience, Dumby.
是人类竞争中上帝之玩笑而已
It's God's joke on the human race.
他确信她已改过自新了
He's quite convinced she'schanged her spots.
想把那变有趣吗?
Care to make it interesting?
告诉你我是认真的了
I told you I was serious.
没有人警告你该反对我吗?
Hasn't anyone warned youagainst me?
哦，是的，所有人
Oh, yes. Everyone.
把它拿开
Put it away.
你并不用马上就爱上我
Now, you don't have to loveme right away.
想想钱
Think of the money.
假设我跟你结婚一年内你的投资缩水了
Suppose I marry you, and in a yearyour investments go sour.
我就被个叫花子栓住了
I'll be stuck with a pauper.
另一个情形是...
On the other hand...
我可能下礼拜二死在高尔夫球场……
I could drop dead on the golf coursenext Tuesday...
而你可就富裕了
and you'd be left verywell-appointed.
生命就是赌博, Stella
Life's a gamble, Stella.
我不知如何作答
I don't know what to say.
人讲太多话
People say too much as it is.
Windemere太太跟Erlynne太太...
Mrs Windemere andMrs Erlynne...
看起来就跟母女是的，是吧?
Iook like mother and daughter,don't they?
他们穿着同样的衣服
They're wearing the same dress.
就是的
Well, that'll be it.
跟我走吧
Come away with me.
我们今晚就出海
We could set sail tonight.
求你
Please.
这是你开玩笑的方式吗？
Is this your idea of a joke?
我得跟你谈谈Darlington
I need to speak to you.It's about Darlington.
跟我来
Follow me.
他爱上Meg了
He's in love with Meg.
我知道我说到钱的问题，我要提高数目让你现在就走
I know we said cash, so I'm raisingthe amount. I want you to leave now.
我要是你会更小心的
I'd be more concernedif I were you.
你不是我
You're not me.
问题是我对我妻子说谎了...
The problem is I've beenlying to my wife...
而我很不在行
and I'm not very good at it.
我可以再添加谣言...
I can add up the rumours...
让她看什么都没有我是Tuppy的女人
and show her a big fat zero.I'm Tuppy's girl.
- 案件结束了- 我自己会解释，你出去吧
- Case closed.- I'll do my own explaining, get out.
我要跟她道别
I'd like to say goodbye to her.
你20年前就跟她道别了没有选择余地
You said goodbye to her twentyyears ago. No second chances.
我先离开
I'll leave first.
- 我们不该一起出去- 你是专家
- We shouldn't walk out together.- You're the expert.
数100下
Count to a 100.
Windemere太太?
Mrs Windemere?
亲爱的Robert, 我以为我们的婚姻是完美的
Dear Robert, I thought ourmarriage was perfect.
我以为我们永远会在一起
I thought we wouldalways be together.
如果你爱Erlynne太太,你该跟他在一起
If you love Mrs Erlynne,you should be with her.
我觉得真愚蠢
I feel so foolish.
每个人都知道，只有我不知道
Everyone knew but me.
Meg, 让我进去我要跟你谈谈
Meg, let me in,I wanna talk to you.
请开门
Please, open the door.
我和Stella Erlynne之间什么都没有
There is nothing between meand Stella Erlynne.
你怎么能那么想?
How can you think it?
上帝她那么老，还染头发
She's old for God's sake.She dyes her hair.
她象印度人一样粉刷她的脸
She paints her facelike an Indian.
她是个冷血自私的女人
She's a cold,selfish woman.
如果你认识她就知道她根本不吸引人
Not all attractiveonce you know her.
她想毁灭一个人
Look, she was goingto damage someone.
一个不会伤害她的人
A person who'd never doneher any harm.
她带来的秘密会伤你的心
She came here with a secret thatwould have broken your heart.
我想告诉你，但不知如何做
Look, I wanted to tell you. I justdidn't know how.
我是想保护你，你得相信我
I was trying to protect you,you have to believe me.
她管我要钱，我给了她...
She asked me for moneyand I gave it to her, but...
我并不以被勒索而自豪...
I'm not proud ofbeing blackmailed...
我不知所措
I didn't know what else to do.
我该开始就告诉你的
I should have told youat the start.
我不打算再骗你了...
I'm not lying to you now, I...
我爱你
I love you.
我心里没有别人...
And there's no otherwoman in my heart...
床上也没有
or in my bed.
Meg...
请开门
please open the door.
我俩都喝太多香槟了
We both had toomuch champagne.
我们明早再谈吧
We can talk in the morning.
- 太棒了- 谢谢你来
- Splendid.- Thank you for coming.
- 晚会不错， Robert.- 我们在俱乐部见
- Lovely party. Goodnight, Robert.- I'll see you at the club.
- 女孩在这里啊-带Windemere去俱乐部
- There's the girl.- Take Windemere to the club.
整晚守着他，如果能就灌醉他
Keep him out all night.Get him drunk if you have to.
- 就是别让他回家- 为什么?
- Just don't let him come home.- Why?
什么啊？
What? What?
我喜欢你，真的
I like you, I do.
但是如果想奏效的话，你就不能那样
But if this is going to workbetween us, you can't do that.
- 哪样？- “哪里？什么？为什么”
- Do what?- "Where? What? Why?"
我不能老解释跟...
I can't always explainmyself to myself...
别人解释自己
let alone anyone else.
不错，放开压力
Good for you -takes the pressure off.
9成的男人...
Nine times out of ten, mendon't give two pins about why...
无法接受被强加的兴趣
they just feel obligedto take an interest.
那么我就按吩咐行事...
So, I'll do exactly as you wish...
假装感觉我们已经结婚了
and I'll feel as ifwe're married already.
哦，你能安全回家吗?
Oh, can you get yourselfhome all right?
哇, Tuppy...
Why, Tuppy...
你是第一个这么问我的男人
you're the first man who'sasked me that.
我不必是第一个Stella，就当最后一个吧
I don't need to be the first,Stella. Just the last.
在码头上有辆出租车等着
There's a taxi waitingat the end of the dock.
我丈夫让你来的
My husband sent you.
你丈夫以为你喝了一瓶矿泉水...
Your husband thinks you'rein bed sleeping off...
已经睡了
a litre of Perrier Jouet.
走吧
Let's go.
他给我钱了，就这样
He gave me money,that's all.
我是家族的老朋友
I'm an old friend of the family.
你以为我傻吗?
Do you think I'm stupid?
嫁给了一个爱的人，又跟...
Married to man you loveand running off...
一个国际花花公子离家?我以为你傻?
with an international playboy?Do I think you're stupid?
这跟你无关
This is none of your business.
你以为开衩变高了，我们可以投票...
You think because hems are higherand women can vote...
一切就会为我们而改变吗?
that anything hasreally changed for us?
朋友们会不跟你联系
Friends will stop calling.
他会受邀回家，而你不会
He'll be invited into homesyou're not.
你可以做到
You manage.
别吓比较
Don't compare yourself.
无悔的生活需要准备和练习
It takes practice andskill to live without regret.
一段婚姻需要你整个心灵
A marriage takesyour whole heart.
自私的人做不到，但你不是
Selfish people can't pull it off,but you're not that.
我们都失败了你也不会
You can succeed wherethe rest of us fail.
- 我干嘛要信你?- 别信我，信他
- Why should I believe you?- Don't believe me, believe him.
他对你是忠诚的，我以性命担保
He's been faithful to you,I'll swear it on my life.
他让你撒谎
He told you to lie.
他甚至不知道你在这
He doesn't evenknow you're here.
他不必知道
He never has to know.
你让我再撒谎吗?
You want me to lie again?
我们间的一切都完了，我不能
Everything's spoiledbetween us. I can't.
你怎么了?
What's happened to you?
谁教你这么不能宽容?
Who taught you to be sounforgiving?
你犯了个错，别再犯了
You made a mistake,don't make it worse.
你对不完美的东西熟视无睹...
You shut your eyes to everythingthat isn't perfect...
你被带向一个陷阱
you're just asking to fallinto a hole.
好吧
Fine.
去吧
Go ahead.
放弃爱而选择傲慢和内疚吧
Step over love to pick uppride and guilt.
真是20岁这一年里
What will that tradebe worth in a year?
最赔了买卖了
In twenty?
Darlington, 你的船非得这么大吗?
Darlington, does your boatreally have to be so big?
你知道人们怎么议论有大船的男人吗？
You know what they say aboutmen with big boats.
- 我得回家了- 你得抽支雪茄，真的?
- I should be getting home.- You'll take a cigar, surely?
我以为你放弃对好女人的爱了呢
I thought you'd quitfor the love of a good woman.
好女人可不是 Erlynne太太的名字
Good woman isn't exactly themoniker I'd choose for Mrs Erlynne.
你在暗示她是魔鬼的侍女吗？
You imply she'sthe devil's handmaiden.
Dumby和我正为你的未来担忧呢
Dumby and I are just concernedfor your future.
魔鬼般的女人是麻烦好女人又太闷了
Devilish women are a bother,and good ones are a bore.
那是唯一的不同
That's the only difference.
Erlynne太太即不是麻烦也不是沉闷
Mrs Erlynne is neither a bothernor a bore.
你改变了习惯但我怀疑她也会改变
You change your habits,but I doubt she'll change hers.
我跟 Dumby 赌了50块
I've bet Dumby fifty quid.
够了
Enough of this.
我不想听反对她的话了
I won't hear any more wordssaid against her.
她是我对女人一切愿望的完美体现
She's everything I've everwanted in a woman.
我亲爱的Tuppy,这世界上只有两个惨剧
My dear Tuppy, in this worldthere are only two tragedies.
一是一无所获，一是得偿所愿
One is not getting what one wants,the other is getting it.
后者是最差的，真正的惨剧
The last is very much the worst.The last is a real tragedy.
婚姻
Marriage.
痛苦万分，问Edna
It has its pains - ask Edna.
单身生活没乐趣
Celibacy has no pleasures.
- 你怎么知道?- 我可以学
- What would you know about it?- I can learn.
来证明我的爱
If it will prove my love.
女人需要验证?
A woman who needs proof?
在她离开她丈夫以前
Before she'll leave her husband.
John,你是个无赖
John, you are a cad.
我们都在臭水沟里
We're all in the gutter.
而我们中的一些人却在看星星
But some of us are looking at the stars.
男人称它为“殷勤”
What men call gallantry...
上帝称它为“通奸”
ans God's adultery...
这种事在天气闷热的地方，尤其容易发生
is far more common where the climate's sultry.
那是我买给Meg的
That's the one I bought Meg.
生日礼物
For her birthday.
你肯定吗?
Are you sure?
必是上次你来吃饭时她落在这的
She must have left it last weekwhen you came for lunch.
可她今晚拿着来着
She was carrying it tonight.
扇子彼此相象
One fan looks very muchlike another.
John?
- 我不知道- Meg不是在这里吧?
- I've no idea.- Meg's not here, is she?
当然不是
No, of course not.
- 那是什么?- 我什么都没听见
- What's that?- I didn't hear anything.
她在楼下
She's downstairs.
冷静你喝太多了...
Calm down.You've had too much...
别让你自己出丑
Don't make an ass of yourself.
太晚了
Too late.
- 该死- 你弄点冰敷上吧
- Bloody hell!- You better put some ice on that.
我以为是我的呢
I thought it was mine.
肯定是误拿了Windemere的
I must have picked upMrs Windemere's by mistake.
Tuppy, 我发誓，我不知道
Tuppy, I swear, I had no idea.
你欠Cecil 50磅，对不起
You owe Cecil fifty quid. Sorry.
好像是我出丑了Windemere，不是你
It seems I'm the ass,Windemere. Not you.
我在John船上过的夜
I spent the night on John's boat.
我喝多了
I had too much to drink.
你能原谅我吗?
Can I ask you to forgive me?
我昨夜做了很蠢的事
I did something very stupidlast night.
你不是我的同伙
You're not in my league.
我出了大丑
I made a complete ass of myself.
毁了Tuppy
Ruined it for poor Tuppy.
但我想这迟早会发生
Better now than later, I guess.
Tuppy?
他取消了向Erlynne太太求婚
His engagement toMrs Erlynne is off.
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
昨晚在John游艇上，Erlynne在他卧室里等他
Last night on John's yacht, MrsErlynne was waiting in his bedroom.
看，我喝多了，我以为...
Look, I was drunk, I thought...
我看见了你的扇子，我以为...
I saw your fan, I thought that...
我没用脑子
I didn't think.
是她
It was her.
她说是她误拿了
She said she took it by mistake.
- 不，那不是事实- 当然不是
- No, that's not true.- Oh, of course not.
最好数数勺子
Better count the spoons.
你不让她来是对的
You were rightnot to want her here.
我对John期望挺高的，Tuppy可是他的朋友啊
I'd have expected more from John,though. Tuppy's his friend.
她没拿我的扇子，我把它...
She didn't take my fan.I left it on the...
有美国的电话
There's a telephone callfrom America.
是你父亲，Windemere 先生
It's your father, Mr Windemere.
现在不行
Not now.
我来接，他会担心的
No, I'll take it.He'll worry.
- 我爱你- 我爱你
- I love you.- I love you.
一个女人送来这个
And a woman brought this.
她在楼下等
She's waiting downstairs.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在这里干嘛?我们有协议
What are you doing here?We had an agreement.
我回来还扇子
I came to return the fan.
你太太今早怎么样?
How is your wifefeeling this morning?
你不许靠近我太太10尺
You don't get within ten feetof my wife.
我只是问候她
I only asked how she was.
如果你来这告诉她你是谁...
If you're here to tellher who you are...
还是我来吧
it's better coming from me.
是我的秘密，不是你的
It's my secret, not yours.
你保守的很好
You've kept it very well.
20年是个很久的时间
Twenty years is a long time.
没造成什么伤害
It doesn't seem to have beentoo much of a strain.
你看个小女孩...
You see a little girl...
合适的岁数把想法放在一边
the right age,you push the thought aside.
关上门
Close the door.
只在三点……
Only at three o'clock,that in-between hour...
干什么都晚了，吃饭有太早...
too late to do anything,too early for dinner...
门大敞着
doors come flying open.
我不觉得你对她有感情
I don't believe you feelanything for her.
你只顾自己，没别人
You care about yourself,and no-one else.
Robert.
你父亲要跟你说话，很重要
Your father needs to talk to you,he says it's important.
Erlynne太太来还你扇子
Mrs Erlynnecame to return your fan.
她刚要走
She was just leaving.
不，别走，我要跟你说话
No, don't leave, I need tospeak with you.
- 她会耽误航班- 就一会儿
- She'll miss her plane.- Just a few minutes.
你父亲在等你接电话，说是重要事
Your father's waiting on the phone.He said it's important.
误航班...
It would be a great mistake...
会是个大错
to miss your plane.
我来确认你安全到家了
I came to make sureyou got home safely.
你还不能走
You can't leave yet.
你是证明没事发生的唯一证人
You're my only witness thatnothing happened.
你的证人?
Your witness?
我要告诉他真相
I'm going to tell him the truth.
你做错了
What you did is your mistake.
你的麻烦，你来扛吧
Your sack of bricks. You carry it.
你不能忏悔后把痛苦留给爱你的人
You don't confess and had it offto someone who loves you.
但所有人都觉得你...
But everybody thinksyou were having...
他们反正要那么想，没关系
They'll think it anyway.It doesn't matter.
那不是真相，对Tuppy来说有关系
That's not true,it matters to Tuppy.
我无法对毁了你们的婚约熟视无睹
I can't be responsiblefor ruining that.
你想把我做过的唯一善举给毁了吗?
You wanna spoil the onegood thing I've ever done?
告诉他真相是对的
It's only right to tell himthe truth.
你们相爱，这就是事实
You love each other!That's your truth.
你干嘛放弃一段好婚姻而拯救我?
Why you giving up your chanceof marriage to save mine?
- 没道理- 我告诉你真相
- It doesn't make any sense.- I'll tell you the truth.
但首先答应我...
But first, promise you're notgoing to make...
不会去做大忏悔
some grand confession.
以圣名起誓
Swear it on whatever youhold sacred.
我以我母亲起誓
I swear on my mother.
什么?
Pardon?
她是我的守护天使
She's my guardian angel.
我的一生，都想象她那样
My whole life, I've wantedto be like her.
我确信她不想你以她为标准
I'm sure she wouldn't hold youto such a standard.
她此时一定以我为耻
She'd be so ashamed of me now.
我们都在深渊挣扎，Windemere太太
We all straddle the abyss,Mrs Windemere.
如果我们不下望又怎能知道自己的真相?
If we never look down, how canwe know who we are?
母亲永远也不会因不堕落的女儿为耻
A mother could never be ashamedof a daughter who didn't fall in.
我希望你对
I hope you're right.
我从未如此确信过
I've never been more certainof anything.
我发誓
I swear, them.
你要告诉我什么?
What is it you wanted to tell me?
没事
Nothing.
我要耽误航班了
I'll miss my plane.
再见， Windemere太太
Goodbye, Mrs Windemere.
我希望我们再见
I hope we meet again.
我也是
So do I.
Erlynne太太
Mrs Erlynne.
- 你没告诉她吧?- 没有
- You didn't tell her?- No.
为什么?
Why not?
她有母亲
She has a mother.
小盒里的照片
A photograph in a locket.
那是个神话
It's a fairy tale.
一个善良、温存的妈妈，爱她，照顾她
A kind, caring mother, who lovesand watches over her.
我不能把那个带走
I'm not going to take that away.
你也不该
And neither should you.
Erlynne太太,1000美元
Mrs Erlynne,One thousand Dollars.
有一晚，我觉得你爱上了其他女人
For one night I thought you were inlove with another woman.
有一晚我以为你爱上了其他男人
For one night I thought you were inlove with another man.
- 她是对的- 谁?
- She was right.- Who?
Erlynne太太说我们不该对...
Mrs Erlynne said we can'tshut our eyes...
不完美熟视无睹...
to everything that isn't perfect...
否则我们会坠入深渊
otherwise we might fallinto a huge abyss.
我们差一点
We almost fell.
她是个聪明的女人
She's a smart woman.
她是个好女人
She's a good woman.
比我想的好
Better than I thought.
她很坚持
She insisted.
谁?
Who?
Meg，一个对她的念想
Meg.Something to remember her by.
而且她解释了一切
And she explained everything.
一切?
Everything?
哦，对，当然瘪轮胎，狗
Oh, yes, couse.The flat tyre, the dog.
巴西出租车司机和怀孕的女儿……
The Brazilian taxi diver with thepregnant daughter...
丢了钱包
who lost her purse.
而我的辩解是...
And the only thing I can sayin my defense is...
我没什么可辩解的
that I have no defense.
我跳到结论，直接往最坏想
I jumped to conclusions andthought the worst.
这破筐往哪去?
Where's this old crate going to?
我不知道
I don't know.
到地方后你会嫁给我吗?
Will you marry me when get there?
男人娶该娶的女人为妻
A man gets the wife he deserves.
而我，可是一个很坏很坏的男人
Well, I've been a very, very bad man.
你知道，John,爱是战场
You know, John,love's a battleground.
而那只是皮肉之伤
It was only a flesh wound.
男人预支，女人隐忍
Men advance,women resist.
我们退缩他们就堵住我们的退路
We retreat and theyblock our escape.
我们不能赢的
We can't win.
两性无法彼此理解
The sexes will never understandeach other.
他们以伤彼此伤害
Only because they take such painsto deceive each other.
哦，Dumby,你醒着吗?
Oh, hello Dumby,are you awake?
我赢了吗?
Am I winning?